Kristijan Rebernisak

Anina 76, 10000 Zagreb, Croatia kristijan@runningbeta.io | +385 91 4554-344

INTERESTS & PROFICIENCY

https://github.com/krebernisak

I have been writing code, running servers and experimenting with new software since 2004. Most recently the majority of code I have written has been in Java and JavaScript, but I have experience in many other languages and technologies. I am a full-stack developer interested in designing and building scalable distributed systems as well as usable mobile and web clients.

- Proficient in Java and JavaScript
- ► Some experience in Solidity, Kotlin/Swift, Python and familiar with C, C++, C#, MATLAB, Ruby and many others
- Well experienced in building applications for the Android platform
- ► Web technologies (HTML5, CSS3, SVG, DOM, AJAX, REST, SOAP, WSDL, JSON, XML)
- ► Relational databases and object-relational mapping (SQL, Hibernate, JDO, JPA)
- ► Non-Relational databases (Firebase, Redis, ElasticSearch, Blockchain)
- ► General knowledge of cryptography and network security
- ► Tools: Git, Mercurial, Gradle, Maven, Ant, UNIX/Linux
- ► Object-oriented design, Domain Driven Design, Test Driven Design, Functional programming
- ► Passion for distributed systems, product design, and agile methodologies

WORK EXPERIENCE

Running Beta a blockchain research company and private investment vehicle

Founder and Technical Lead, Aug 2017

- ► Distributed protocol design and system architecture
- ► Token economics and mechanism design research and prototyping
- ► Ethereum smart contract development
- ► Technologies: Ethereum, Solidity, Truffle, web3.js, IPFS

Bellabeat an Health-Tracking intelligence platform for women

Mobile Team Lead, Sep 2015 - Mar 2017

- ► Lead a team of 10 engineers (iOS, Android, QA)
- ► High-level system architecture and technology strategy design and implementation
- ► Native Android mobile app, Bellabeat Leaf, architecture, and implementation
- ► Core Java shared (Android, Backend, iOS J2Objc) library architecture, and implementation
- Pushed adoption of functional-reactive programming on multiple projects and platforms
- ► Technologies: Java, Android SDK, Bluetooth LE, Reactive Streams (RxJava, RxSwift), Firebase, J2Objc, ElasticSearch, Kotlin

ShoutEm mobile app builder

Android Developer, May 2013 - Sep 2015

- ► Design and develop a hybrid Android/HTML5 mobile app
- ► Redesigned an Android native wrapper to run the HTML5 application
- ► Decreased Android code base by 25% after four weeks of work
- ► Developing features and architecture for an HTML5 application that was deployed to thousands of users on iOS, Android and across mobile and desktop browsers
- Working closely with server team designing backend REST API
- ► Loyalty module lead developer and architecture design
- ► Using a local proxy server enabled podcast streaming for US Sprint users
- Assisted in architecture planning and building of an in-house data collecting system

► Technologies: Java, Android SDK & NDK, Apache Cordova, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, ElasticSearch, Ruby, Python

Five Minutes Ltd. now FIVE - Mobile App Design and Development Agency

Android Developer, November 2012 - May 2013

- ► Developing Android apps for various enterprise clients like Allianz, The Hearst Corporation, Konzum and startups like Fogg Mobile and Visiobike.
- ► Bluetooth protocol communication with hardware controller used by an electric bicycle
- ► Ad hoc wifi webcam streaming in MJPEG video format
- Technologies: Android SDK & NDK, Maven, Ant, RoboGuice, Otto, kSOAP 2, Bluetooth, SQL

Real Networks

Java EE Developer, CUEComm, April 2012 - November 2012

- ► SOAP API backend used by MEP Storefront
- ► Rewritten from the ground up for better scalability and maintenance
- Extensive testing with SoapUI and JMeter
- ► Technologies: J2EE, Spring, SOAP, Hibernate, JBoss, Ant, Solr

Java EE Developer, MEP Storefront, February 2011 - April 2012

- Media Entertainment Platform for providing music, ringtones and ringback tones to mobile carrier users
- ► Designed and implemented features for some major mobile carriers in the US (MetroPCS, Verizon, Sprint) and EU
- ► Implemented SSO for clients applications using Oracle OpenSSO Fedlet
- ► Technologies: J2EE, JSP, SOAP, WSDL, JBoss portal, Tomcat, Maven, SAML 2.0

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE June 2011 Faculty of electrical engineering and computing, University of Zagreb

Graduation Thesis Eigenphase Based Recognition System for Partially Occluded Faces

- ► This approach combines a Principal component analysis (PCA) with Linear discriminant analysis (LDA) using Fourier transform phase information to extract the facial features and reduce the dimensionality of the feature space
- ► Written in MATLAB and tested on AR Face Database and XM2VTSDB

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTING July 2009 Faculty of electrical engineering and computing, University of Zagreb

BSc Thesis Hand-written Alphanumerical Character Recognition

- Pattern recognition classification of 30 Croatian letters and numbers from 0 to 9
- ► Contour features were extracted using Fourier and Granlund descriptors
- ► K-nearest-neighbor (kNN) classification
- ► Written in Java

SIDE PROJECTS

KiM (www.kimtoys.com, www.kimtrgovina.hr) - 2009

- ► Online catalog and content management system (CMS).
- ► Running on Google App Engine platform.
- Written in Java on Struts 2 Framework using Struts Tiles, Java Data Objects (JDO), Apache Lucene and other.

- Redeployed as a new website in 2015 using Magento v1.8.1 e-commerce platform, running in Docker containers on Digital Ocean
 Updated to Magento v2.1.9 in 2017, running in Docker containers on Google Compute Engine